A Guide to the Executive Papers of Governor Thomas B. Stanley, 1954-1958
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
A Guide to the Executive Papers of Governor Thomas B. Stanley, 1954-1958
The Library of Virginia
23344a
56 cu. ft. (158 boxes)
Stanley, Thomas B., Records of Virginia Governor
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Accession 25184 transferred from the Office of the Governor, 1960 May 24.
Biographical Information
Thomas Bahnson Stanley was born in Henry County, Virginia on 16 July 1890. From 1930 to 1946, he represented Henry County and Martinsville in the Virginia House of Delegates, serving as speaker of the house from 1942 to 1946. He was elected to the United States House of Representatives in 1946, serving until 1953, the same year he was elected Governor of Virginia. Stanley died in Martinsville, Virginia on 10 July 1970.
Scope and Content
The Executive Papers of Governor Thomas B. Stanley are housed in 158 boxes. The collection is arranged into eight (8) series. Series have been designated for: I. State Government. II. Judicial. III. General Assembly. IV. General Correspondence. V. Extraditions. VI. Federal Government. VII. Invitations. VIII. Miscellaneous. These records include applications, appointments, correspondence, executive orders, extraditions, invitations, minutes, proclamations, recommendations, reports, and speeches. These records document the gubernatorial administration of Thomas B. Stanley from 20 January 1954 to 11 January 1958.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I. State Government
Series II: Judicial
Series III: General Assembly
Series IV: General Correspondence
Series V: Extraditions
Series VI: Federal Government
Series VII: Invitations
Series VIII: Miscellaneous
Contents List
- Series I: State Government, 1954-1958., Extent: 19.6 cu. ft. (56 boxes). (Box Boxes 1-56)
  The State Government records are housed in 56 boxes and are arranged alphabetically by agency or subject. Subjects include: Alcoholic Beverage Control Board, Boards, Commissions (including Art Commission, Elizabeth River Tunnel Commission, and Hampton Roads Sanitation Commission), Department of Conservation and Development (including Virginia Conservation Commission), Virginia Corporation Commission, Education (Advisory Research Committee on School Construction, State Board of Education, Superintendent of Public Instruction, and colleges and universities), Governor's Mansion, Grounds and Buildings, Department of Health, Department of Highways, Department of Mental Hygiene and Hospitals (includes mental hospitals), Military Affairs (Adjutant General), State Police, Taxation, Unemployment Compensation Commission, Virginia Ports Authority, Virginia Supplemental Retirement System, and Department of Welfare and Institutions (Corrections, Penitentiary, and Parole Board).
  Arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  - Accounts and Purchases, Dept. of (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Accounts and Purchases, Dept. of, Comptroller, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Accounts and Purchases, Dept. of, Comptroller, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Accounts and Purchases, Dept. of, Comptroller, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Accounts and Purchases, Dept. of, Comptroller, Chief Pension Clerk (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Accounts and Purchases, Dept. of, Purchase and Printing, Division of (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Accounts and Purchases, Dept. of, Purchase and Printing, Division of, Release for Approved Standards, etc. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Agriculture, Commodity Distribution (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Agriculture, Pasture Improvement Committee (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Agriculture, Production and Marketing (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Agriculture and Immigration, Dept. of, State Agriculture Commission (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Agriculture and Immigration, Dept. of, Appointment of Commissioner of (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Agriculture and Immigration, Dept. of, Board of Agriculture and Immigration (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Agriculture and Immigration, Dept. of, Commissioner of Agriculture and Immigration (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Agriculture and Immigration, Dept. of, Recommendations, Dept. of Agriculture (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Agriculture and Immigration, Dept. of, Drought, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Alcoholic Beverage Control, Dept. of (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Alcoholic Beverage Control, Dept. of, Control Board, Monthly Reports (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Alcoholic Beverage Control, Dept. of, Control Board, Quarterly Reports (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Atlantic Rural Exposition Committee (Box 3, Folder 6-7)
  - Auditor of Public Accounts (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Barter Theatre, Virginia Conservation Commission (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Boards, Board of Examiners, Division of Mines (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Boards, Governor and Advisory Board on Mental Hygiene (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Boards, Professional and Occupational Registration, Dept. of Special Board of Examiners on (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Boards, Basic Science (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Boards, State Board for the Examination and Certification of Architects, Engineers and Surveyors (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Boards, State Board of Accountancy (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Boards, State Board of Certification of Librarians (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Boards, State Board of Commissioners to Examine Pilots (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Boards, State Board of Dental Examiners (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Boards, State BOard of Elections (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Boards, State Board of Embalmers and Funeral Directors (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Boards, State Board of Examiners in Optometry (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Boards, State Board of Medical Examiners (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Boards, State Board of Nurse Examiners (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Boards, State Board of Opticians (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Boards, State Board of Pharmacy Examiners (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Boards, State Board of Veterinary Examiners (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Boards, State Dry Cleaners Board (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Boards, State Registration Board for Contractors (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Boards, State Water Control Board (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Budget, Division of the (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Budget, Division of the, Matters brought to the budget (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Budget, Division of the, Governor's Advisory Board (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Budget, Division of the, James Monroe Memorial Foundation (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Commissions, Advisory Council on the Virginia Economy (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Commissions, Advisory Legislative Council, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Commissions, Advisory Legislative Council, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Commissions, Advisory Legislative Council, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Commissions, Aging, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Commissions, Aging, 1956-1958 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Commissions, Airport Facilities Study Commission, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Commissions, Alexander Hamilton Bi-Centennial Commission (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Commissions, Art Commission (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Commissions, Art Commission, Meetings-Notices (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Commissions, Art Commission, Minutes (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Commissions, Athletic (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Commissions, Atlantic Marine Fisheries (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Commissions, Beach Erosion (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Commissions, Bright Flue Cured Tobacco (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Commissions, Chesapeake Bay Ferry (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Commissions, Coastal Turnpike Authority (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Commissions, Code Recodification (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Commissions, Fix Salaries of Trial Justices (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Commissions, Council of Higher Education (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Commissions, Elizabeth River Tunnel (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Commissions, Fisheries, 1954-1957 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Commissions, Fisheries, Appointment (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Commissions, Fisheries Laboratory (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Commissions, Flouridation Study, 1956-1958 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Commissions, Fuel (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Commissions, Game and Inland Fisheries (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Commissions, Game and Inland Fisheries, Appointments (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Commissions, Game and Inland Fisheries, Recommendations (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Commissions, Game and Inland Fisheries, Recommendations, Sam P. Goodloe (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Commissions, Game and Inland Fisheries, Recommendations, Dr. J.C. Overby (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Commissions, Game and Inland Fisheries, Recommendations, J.M. Tusing (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Commissions, Game and Inland Fisheries, Recommendations, Isaac T. Walke, Jr. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Commissions, Hampton Road Sanitation (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Commissions, History of Government Textbook (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Commissions, Industrial Development (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Commissions, Interstate Commission on the Potomac River Basin (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Commissions, Interstate Cooperation (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Commissions, Local debt (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Commissions, Milk (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Commissions, Ohio River Valley Water Sanitation (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Commissions, Overall Advisory Council on needs of Handicapped Children (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Commissions, Potomac River Oyster (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Commissions, Public Buildings (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Commissions, Real Estate (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Commissions, Richmond Produce Market Authority (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Commissions, State Museum of Science (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Commissions, Tax Study, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Commissions, Uniformity of Legislation (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Commissions, Veterans Affairs (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Commissions, Visually Handicapped (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Commissions, Wrecks (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Common Glory (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Conservation and Development, Dept. of (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Conservation and Development, Dept. of, Director, 1954-1955 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Conservation and Development, Dept. of, Director, 1956-1957 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Conservation and Development, Dept. of, Division of Forest Wardens (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Conservation and Development, Dept. of, Division of Forest Wardens (Box 13, Folder 1-3)
  - Conservation and Development, Dept. of, Division of Geology (Box 13, Folder 4-5)
  - Conservation and Development, Dept. of, Virginia Conservation Commission (Box 13, Folder 6-7)
  - Conservation and Development, Dept. of, Virginia State Planning Board (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Conservation and Development, Dept. of, Virginia State Planning Board (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Conservation and Development, Dept. of, Division of Water Resources Board (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Corporation Commission, 1954 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Corporation Commission, 1955 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Corporation Commission, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Corporation Commission, 1957 Jan.-June (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Corporation Commission, 1957 July-Dec. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Corporation Commission, Advisory Committee on Civil Aeronautics (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Corporation Commission, Advisory Commission on Aviation (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Corporation Commission, Bureau of Banking (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Corporation Commission, Bureau of Insurance (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Corporation Commission, Fire Marshall (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Corporation Commission, Public Utilities (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Corporation Commission, Recommendations, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Education, Advisory Research Committee on School Construction (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Education, Board of, 1954 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Education, Board of, 1955 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Education, Board of, 1956-1957 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Education, Commission on Public Education, 1954 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Education, Commission on Public Education, 1955 (Box 19, Folder 1-2)
  - Education, Commission on Public Education, 1956-1957 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Education, Educational Vocational Training (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Education, Literary Fund (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Education, Public Education, 1955 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Education, Rehabilitation and Adult Education (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Education, Virginia Retirement of Public School Teachers (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Education, Scholarships (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Education, School, Bonds (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Education, School, Manuals (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Education, School, Problems, 1954 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Education, School, Problems, 1955 (Box 20, Folder 3-4)
  - Education, School, Problems, 1956 Jan.-June (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Education, School, Problems, 1956 July-Dec. (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Education, School, Problems, 1957 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Education, School, Program, 1953 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Education, School, Program, 1954 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Education, School, Program, 1955 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Education, School, Program, 1956-1957 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Education, School, Transportation (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Education, Study of Year-Round Use of Facilities (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Education, Superintendent of Public Instruction, 1955-1956 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Education, Superintendent of Public Instruction, 1957 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Education, Superintendent of Public Instruction, Recommendations (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Education, Supreme Court Decision regarding pupil placement (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Education, Surplus property (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Education, Teachers (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Education, 12 month school plan (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Education, Veterans (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Education, Virginia Conference on Education (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Education, Virginia Education Association (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Education, Virginia Education Facilities Committee, Stanley 1957 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Education, Woodrow Wilson Rehabilitation Center (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Education, Schools, College of William and Mary, 1954 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Education, Schools, College of William and Mary, 1955 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Education, Schools, College of William and Mary, 1956-1957 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Education, Schools, College of William and Mary, Board of Visitors (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Education, Schools, College of William and Mary, Board of Visitors, 1954-1957 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Education, Schools, College of William and Mary, Board of Visitors, Appointments (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Education, Schools, College of William and Mary, Board of Visitors, Recommended (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Education, Schools, College of William and Mary, Norfolk Division (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Education, Schools, Longwood College (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Education, Schools, Madison College (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Education, Schools, Medical College of Virginia, Board of Visitors (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Education, Schools, Richmond Professional Institute (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Education, Schools, University of Virginia (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Education, Schools, University of Virginia, Board of Visitors (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Education, Schools, University of Virginia, Board of Visitors, Recommendations, 1954 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Education, Schools, University of Virginia, Board of Visitors, Recommendations, James L. Camblos (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Education, Schools, University of Virginia, Board of Visitors, Recommendations, W.M. Camp (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Education, Schools, University of Virginia, Board of Visitors, Recommendations, Horace Gray (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Education, Schools, University of Virginia, Board of Visitors, Recommendations, Robert V. Hatcher (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Education, Schools, University of Virginia, Clinch Valley (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Education, Schools, University of Virginia, Fulbright Scholarships (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Education, Schools, University of Virginia, Hospital Division (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Education, Schools, University of Virginia, Extension (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Education, Schools, University of Virginia, Mary Washington (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Education, Schools, University of Virginia, School of Foreign Service (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Education, Schools, Virginia Military Institute (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Education, Schools, Virginia Military Institute, Board of Visitors (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Education, Schools, Virginia Military Institute, Board of Visitors, Recommendations (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Education, Schools, Virginia Military Institute, Board of Visitors, Recommendations, Burr P. Harrison (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Education, Schools, Virginia Military Institute, Board of Visitors, Recommendations, Giles H. Miller (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Education, Schools, Virginia Polytechnic Institute, Board of Visitors (Box 29, Folder 1-2)
  - Education, Schools, Virginia Polytechnic Institute, Board of Visitors, Recommendations (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Education, Schools, Virginia Polytechnic Institute, Boys State and Girls State (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Education, Schools, Virginia Polytechnic Institute, Experiment Station (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Education, Schools, Virginia Polytechnic Institute, Extension Division (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Education, Schools, Virginia Polytechnic Institute, Extension Division, County Agents (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Education, Schools, Virginia Polytechnic Institute, Radford (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Education, Schools, Virginia Polytechnic Institute, State Soil Conservation Commission (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Education, Schools, Virginia School for the Deaf and Blind (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Education, Schools, Virginia School for the Deaf and Blind, Board of Visitors (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Education, Schools, Virginia School for the Deaf and Blind, Investigation (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Education, Schools, Virginia State College (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Education, Schools, Virginia State School, Hampton (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Education, Schools, Virginia Truck Experiment Station (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Governor's Mansion (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Governor's Mansion, Social Events (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Governor's Office (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Governor's Office, Addenda (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Governor's Office, Capital Outlay Study (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Governor's Office, Memorandum from Budget Office (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Governor's Office, Reorganization (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Governor's Staff, Appointments (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Grounds and Buildings Section, Director of, 1954-1955 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Grounds and Buildings Section, Director of, 1956 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Grounds and Buildings Section, Director of, 1957 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Gunston Hall, Board of Visitors (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Health, Dept. of, Advisory Council on Tuberculosis Control (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Health, Dept. of, Advisory Hospital Council (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Health, Dept. of, Bureau of Vital Statistics (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Health, Dept. of, Commissioner of (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Health, Dept. of, Commissioner, Recommendations (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Health, Dept. of, Geriatrics (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Health, Dept. of, Hospital Facilities (Richmond, Va.) (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Health, Dept. of, State Board of Health (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Health, Dept. of, State Chief Medical Examiner (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Health, Dept. of, Blue Ridge Sanatorium (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Health, Dept. of, Catawba Sanatorium (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Highways, Dept. of, 1955 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Highways, Dept. of, Appointments (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Highways, Dept. of, Chesapeake Bay Crossing (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Highways, Dept. of, Chesapeake Bay Ferry (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Highways, Dept. of, Chesapeake Bridge (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Highways, Dept. of, Commission, 1954 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Highways, Dept. of, Commission, 1955-1956 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Highways, Dept. of, Commission, 1957 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Highways, Dept. of, Commissioner, 1954 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Highways, Dept. of, Commissioner, 1955 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Highways, Dept. of, Commissioner, 1956 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Highways, Dept. of, Commissioner, 1957 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Highways, Dept. of, Ferry Control (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Highways, Dept. of, Governor's Highway Safety Commission, 1954 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Highways, Dept. of, Governor's Highway Safety Commission, 1955 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Highways, Dept. of, Governor's Highway Safety Commission, 1956 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Highways, Dept. of, Governor's Highway Safety Commission, Recommendations (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Highways, Dept. of, Highways (Box 37, Folder 3-4)
  - Highways, Dept. of, Highways, National State Highway (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Highways, Dept. of, Highways, Old Dominion Turnpike (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Highways, Dept. of, Highways, Recommendations (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Highways, Dept. of, Highways, Richmond-Petersburg Toll Road Authority (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Industrial Commission (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Industrial Commission, Dept. of Workmen's Compensation (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Industrial Commission, Recommendations (Box 39, Folder 3-4)
  - Industrial Commission, Recommendations, M. Edward Evans (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Labor and Industry, Dept. of, Apprenticeship Council (Box 39, Folder 6-7)
  - Labor and Industry, Dept. of (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Labor and Industry, Dept. of, Commissioner of Mines (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Labor and Industry, Dept. of, Commissioner of Mines, Recommendations (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Labor and Industry, Dept. of, Commissioner of Mines, Recommendations, Edmond N. Boggs (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Labor and Industry, Dept. of, Commissioner of Mines, Recommendations, J. Newton Maxey (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Mental Hygiene and Hospitals, Dept. of, 1955 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Mental Hygiene and Hospitals, Dept. of, 1955-1956 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Mental Hygiene and Hospitals, Dept. of, 1957 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Mental Hygiene and Hospitals, Dept. of, Commissioner of, 1954 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Mental Hygiene and Hospitals, Dept. of, Commissioner of, 1956-1957 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Mental Hygiene and Hospitals, Dept. of, Division of Mental Health Director, 1956 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Mental Hygiene and Hospitals, Dept. of, Division of Mental Health Director, 1957 Jan.-June (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Mental Hygiene and Hospitals, Dept. of, Division of Mental Health Director, 1957 July-Dec. (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Mental Hygiene and Hospitals, Dept. of, Reciprocal agreement (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Mental Hygiene and Hospitals, Dept. of, Recommendations (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Mental Hygiene and Hospitals, Dept. of, State Hospital Board, 1954 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Mental Hygiene and Hospitals, Dept. of, State Hospital Board, 1955 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Mental Hygiene and Hospitals, Dept. of, State Hospital Board, 1956 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Mental Hygiene and Hospitals, Dept. of, State Hospital Board, 1957 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Mental Hygiene and Hospitals, Dept. of, State Hospital Board, Investigation (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Mental Hygiene and Hospitals, Dept. of, Eastern State Hospital (Box 44, Folder 2-3)
  - Mental Hygiene and Hospitals, Dept. of, Central State Hospital (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Mental Hygiene and Hospitals, Dept. of, Lynchburg State Colony (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Mental Hygiene and Hospitals, Dept. of, Southwestern State Hospital (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Mental Hygiene and Hospitals, Dept. of, Western State Hospital (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Military Affairs, Dept. of, Adjutant General, 1954 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Military Affairs, Dept. of, Adjutant General, 1955 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Military Affairs, Dept. of, Adjutant General, 1956 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Military Affairs, Dept. of, Adjutant General, Recommendation (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Military Affairs, Dept. of, Adjutant General, Military Board (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Military Affairs, Dept. of, Adjutant General, National Guard (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Motor Vehicles, Division of, Commissioner C.H. Lamb (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Motor Vehicles, Division of, Division of Licenses, Tags (Box 46, Folder 4)